大家好
TIMOTHY JORDAN: Hi, everybody.
[啪啪啪]
papapa
谢谢
Thank you.
我真是受宠若惊
I have a cheering section.
That's amazing.
大家感觉怎么样
How's everybody doing?
觉得这次IO大会如何
Having a good I/O?
后面还会有几个分享
Just got a few more sessions to go.
非常感谢各位来听我的分享
I'm glad that you made it out to this point.
我叫 Timothy Jordan
I'm Timothy Jordan.
今天我要讲的是Google的普适计算
And this is Ubiquitous Computing with Google.
我们已经讨论了好多关于
Now, we've all been talking a lot lately
普适计算 物联网 可穿戴设备 等等
about ubiquitous computing, IOT, wearables, and so on.
当然 我们还有好多要做的
And there's a lot we're going to be able to do together
帮助我们的用户和技术
to help make our users' relationship to technology
联系更紧密
better.
这是我们后面要做的
And this is the next step.
开始之前
Before I get started, please know
我想让你知道你可以反馈给我
that you can give me feedback.
IO主办方希望得到
The I/O overlords would like to know
你的看法 不管是大会本身 相关活动
what you think of this and similar content
还是某个具体的分享
and this session in particular.
所以希望各位可以去app 或网页上
So just head over to the schedule
填一下这张反馈表
either on the app or the web.
谈谈你的想法
And tell us what you think.
OK.
去年的这个时候 我就站在这个地方
So a year ago, I stood on this or a very similar stage.
当时 我分享了关于Google可穿戴设备相关的东西
And I talked to you about wearable computing with Google.
围绕这个论点
I put forth this idea of computing
我更多的从用户角度出发
that was more about the user than the device
而不是设备平台
that they carried.
我们探讨了它的启示
And we explored the implications of that and code design
并且通过分析NPC的问题探讨了代码设计相关问题
by looking at the problem through NPC,
简单 直接 关注空间
simple and straightforward, thinking about the space.
几天 我们将要实践这些观点
Today, we're going to take those ideas and build upon them.
接下来的时间 我们将深入的了解
In this session, we're going to take a deeper look
一些平台和工具
at the platforms and tools that can
通过它们 你可以让你的app实现多设备通用
make your app available on a variety of form factors,
不只是可穿戴设备 也可以是电视机
not just across wearables, but something that's available
车上 甚至是任何地方
on your television and in your car and someday,
even more places.
我们将会更深一步探讨这样的设计
And we'll explore the implications of that design
通过你现在检出和编译的代码
through code that you can check out and compile today.
现在进入正题
Let's get started.
首先 什么是普适计算
So first off, what is ubiquitous computing?
它是对 只要用户需要
It's simply a fancy phrase for technology
他们随时随地可以访问 这种技术的概括
that's accessible to the user whenever and wherever they
want or need it.
这样
That's it.
比如骑车出行的时候
It could be outside when they're going for a bike ride
比如和朋友一起看搞笑视频的时候
or having some friends over to watch cat videos.
比如 在自驾短途旅行的时候
Or maybe it's time for a road trip.
你的用户很可能遇到这样的情形
Your users can be in any of those situations.
你不想让他们考虑他们需要什么样的设备
And you don't want them to have to think about what device they
才能访问你的服务
need to get to your service.
相反 你希望通过构建一个在他们身边现成的设备上可用的app
Instead, you're going to want an experience that presents itself
来为用户提供
to the user wherever it makes sense
随时随地满足用户需要的体验
by building an app that runs on whatever device
they have nearby.
大部分人看到的计算机的演化都是
And many people look at the evolution of computing
像这样的
like this.
关注点总是在下一代设备
It's always about the next device-- big computer,
大型机 小型机 微型机
little computer, littler computer.
在这个进化路线的下一个是什么呢
What's the next thing in this linear progression?
实际上 现在以及今后
But really, our present and future
的发展非常不一样
looks quite a bit different.
更像这样 对不
It looks a lot more like this, right?
我们用不同的方式使用一堆技术
We use a bunch of technology in different ways.
有时是同时使用
And we often do that simultaneously.
实际上 这些设备的发展
In fact, the growth of these connected devices
是惊人的
is staggering.
尽管2020年的数字说法不同
Although the number in 2020 depends
可能有些差别
on who you ask-- it can be a little bit different--
但是绝对是超出你的想象的
It's always more than you can imagine.
我先不告诉大家图上的单位是多少
Now, I didn't throw out the units here.
有人能说一下你觉得单位是多少吗
Does anybody want to tell me what the units are there?
百万
Millions?
是十亿
It's billions.
到2020年将有2000亿设备
200 billion devices in 2020.
你也可以换个方式理解
And you can actually break this number down because 200 billion
因为2000亿有点太多抽象了
is sort of like this abstract number.
想像一下
Think of it this way.
到2020年 人均26台智能设备
26 smart devices for every human on the planet in 2020.
相 当 多
A lot.
但现在不是每个人都有26台智能设备
But not everybody has 26 in their pockets at the same time,
对吗
right?
不同行业之间差别很大
This is across industries.
但是想一下全世界现有的
But think about the number of devices that are going to be
和即将发行的设备
and already are in our world.
这是另一组数据
Here's another number for you.
这非常有意思 尤其是对我们来说
Hey, this is really interesting, especially for us, right?
高德纳公司预测 半数以上的物联网解决方案
Gartner has estimated half of IOT solutions
将在三年内涌现
will be from startups less than three years old.
半数
Half.
那么问题来了 你已经准备好
So the question really is, have you already started
投入到这场运动中了吗
building for this reality?
好消息是这并不是非常难
The good news is it's not that hard to deal with, not as hard
至少不像它看上去那么难
as it might seem.
新功能的爆发式增长取决于
The explosion in form factors is manageable by having
一个强大的以可扩展性为方向的核心平台
a strong core platform that lends itself to extensibility.
你可以少浪费点时间关心多平台问题
So you can think less about a new project for each new device
把精力放在为新功能
and more about a versatile solution
设计通用的实现方案
that you can extend for new form factors
让他们变得可用
as they become available.
这些平台可以帮助你 现在已经有了
And these platforms that help you, they exist today.
给大家展示一个例子
I'm going to show you a working example in a bit.
在编码之前
But before we dig into some code,
这是它的逻辑结构
this is what it looks like logically.
传统的多平台支持形式
Now, the traditional approach to supporting different devices
是为每种设备和平台构建一个app
is to make an app for each device and platform
以便让用户使用
as they become available and adopted by users.
像不像
Like my animation?
几乎就是单独为每一个设备
This has typically meant a new project
做开发和支持
for each and every device developed and supported
independently.
疯了吧
Just crazy.
讽刺的是 我们开发者已经对这种情况
And the ironic thing is that we as developers are already
习以为常了
thinking about this experience as part
觉得这是跨平台开发中很自然的一部分
of a single whole experience for the user across devices.
这种分别进行开发的方式其实是很蠢的
It's just silly to approach these as separate projects.
相反 你应该好好看一下
Instead, you want to take the longer lens view.
如果在每一类设备上的
Think about having a view into your service from each
是视图
and every device that makes sense.
模型和控制器在中央设备
Your model and controller are on a central device
或者在云上
or in the cloud.
这样的话 可穿戴设备 智能家居
But then the wearable, in the living room,
车载设备 通过视图访问服务
in the car's a different view into that service.
这就回到了普适计算的定义上来了
And this is the definition of ubiquitous computing
对吗
again, right?
这就是 你的服务
It's where your service is available
可以随时随地的访问
anywhere and everywhere.
你和你的service
Now, each of you and your service
需要做个区分 对吗
is going to differ slightly, right?
在手机上何在车载设备商
It's going to look a little bit different on the wrist
应该有些区别
than it will in the car.
这就是你要花时间考虑的了
And that's what you want to spend your time on.
你不许需要浪费时间
You don't want to have to spend your time on figuring out
解决兼容性问题
the glue in between all these things.
下面我们直接看一下最佳实践的例子
So what we'll do is we'll jump right into best practices
然后我们再来总结一下这类经验
here so that we can think about how to conceptualize
that experience.
人们再也不用坐在桌子前
And people no longer need to sit at a desk
才能享受科技的便利
to get the benefits of technology.
我们提供的体验远远超出了
Experiences that we build can do more than just
这类用途 对吗
allow for that usage, right?
我刚才说过 人们可以在任何地方
As I've been saying, they can assume that usage
任何时间 使用
throughout the day and in the world.
他们不止能使用我们生活中
They can do more than just work nicely
已经有的技术
with existing technology in our lives.
还能无缝地在他们之间切换
They can work seamlessly across all of it.
现在 记住刚才提到的东西 下面有一些最佳实践
Now, with that in mind, these best practices
可以帮助我们理清楚
will help us navigate the issues, big and small,
如何才能这样开发 一些大大小小的注意点
that we develop in this way.
有一点需要注意的是
And a note about these best practices
它们可以给你提供的指导
is that they're guidelines that apply
不仅是单个设备上的体验
to your experience on each device
还有多平台上提供更好的体验
as well as the greater experience across all devices,
后者也是最佳实践的一个判断标准
which is a great litmus test for best practices in this area.
同时在宏观和微观层面
And make them great for ubiquitous computing
考虑如何让他们的普适计算
when you're thinking about both the smaller
做得更好
picture and the bigger picture across everything
at the same time.
第一点很常见 简单
The first one is sort of obvious, simple.
考虑一下这种场景
Now, think about it this way.
用户体验要求做到非常简单
The user experience should be so simple
简单到毫不费力 就像魔法一样
that it feels effortless, almost magical.
长期来看 用户更倾向于简单和稳定
In the long run, users always prefer
而不是功能的质量
simplicity and reliability over quantity of features.
不管你是解决用户的什么问题
Whatever user problem you solve, make
一定要牢牢记住这一点
sure to address that really well.
更不要做反其道而行的事
And never get in the way of that solution.
消息应用是个很好的例子
A great example of this is a messaging app.
我非常喜欢Android Wear上的消息通知
I love messaging on Android Wear.
我收到一条消息
I get a message.
然后我可以语音回复
And I can reply by voice.
非常的简单直接
It's so intuitive and simple.
就是很自然
It just makes sense.
第二点是 情景模式
The next one is contextual.
关注情境其实就是关注需要的
Now, being contextual is really about being relevant.
把时间 地点 甚至是用户参与的活动考虑在内
Take into account the time, the location, and even the activity
然后随时随地为用户
the user's involved in to provide them
提供最需要的
with the most useful experience wherever they happen to be.
举个例子 我非常喜欢 购物清单这个设置
As an example, I love the idea of a shopping list
当我走进商店的时候 就自动打开了
that automatically comes up as I get into the store
在我离开的时候 可能还会发送一个通知关于
and, before I leave, maybe sends me a notification of any items
我可能遗漏的事情
I might have missed.
就象这样 在用户要求之前
In this case, we're providing information to the user
我们就向他们提供
before they have to ask because we're
因为我们考虑到了他们所处的场景
taking into account their context for them, which
这让我想到这一点
leads me to this idea.
用户体验要求非常迅速 迅速到即时的程度
The experience should be so fast that it should feel immediate.
情景模式可以做到这一点
Now, being contextual can help with this.
不过这还是微交互方面的
But it's also about micro-interactions.
记住你不是打断和占用用户
Remember that you're not trying to distract and occupy
the user.
你只是在恰当的时候提供恰当的信息
You want to present just the right information
让用户可以得到想要的
right away so they can get what they need
还不影响他们的正常生活
and keep living their lives.
一个很好的例子就是Android TV上的语音搜索
A great example of this is Voice Search on Android TV.
用户说他们想看什么
The user can say what show they want to watch.
任何设置了搜索的应用
And any app that's set up for search
就会启动他们想看的
can launch that content for them.
还有一个就是
Another great example is Auto Play and queuing
Google Cast上的自动播放和排队
on Google Cast.
下一集可以立即播放
The next episode can just come right on
用户不需要停下来
so the user doesn't have to stop and find it
在他们看得正high的时候
when they're binge watching.
就像我周末那样
I do on the weekends.
最后一个 扩展性
The last thing is extensible.
你想要构建你的应用
And you're going to want to build your app
和体验 尽可能的可扩展
and experience to be as extensible as possible.
未来的用户会希望
Where are the places that your user will want
用户服务在哪些地方呢
to user service in the future?
你怎么才能把它加进你的核心应用
And how can you build that into your core app
让用户有需要的时候能够
now so that the overall experience that the user has
随时随地的看到所有的体验
is in hand whenever and wherever it makes sense for them?
就是这样
So those are them.
举个例子 音乐
Oh, an example of this-- music.
我想在任何时候 我想听音乐了
I love listening to music wherever I want.
就会播放 每个人都希望这样
And it turns out, I think, everybody's that way.
可能是待在卧室里
That might be at home in the living room.
可能是外出 在跑步或在车里
That might be on the go while I'm on a run or in the car.
现在 几个原则
So there you are-- a handful of principles
帮助你重新定义你的用户体验设计
to help you refine the design of your user experience
帮助你有效地获取用户
and reach your users in an undeniably useful way.
真的有效
That's really key.
我们发现当和开发者们一起工作的时候
We found when working with developers
这些指导方针很有用
that these guidelines help the most when working with new form
当开发新的功能
factors, understanding right away how
理解 描述你的工作
to contextualize and measure your work for success.
这也是我们为什么创造了 设计冲刺技术
And that's why we created a design sprint technique
用来学习实际开发新功能的设计原则
for learning the design principles for new form factors
in particular.
关于设计冲刺的材料
The material for one of these design sprints
我们昨天早上刚刚公布在了
was just launched yesterday morning
developers.google.com上
on developers.google.com.
许多来得早的朋友可能会在座位上
And many of you who arrived a session early
看到一个指南
may have found a play book on your seat.
设计冲刺
Design sprints are a great way to learn immediately
and to try out design principles for these new form factors.
然后你们可以应用在自己的项目中
And then you can apply them to your own project
因为已经非常熟悉了
with the comfort of familiarity.
好的
All right.
看一下具体的方案
Let's look at a practical solution, shall we?
一个你可以下载 编译 修改
One that you can download, compile, adjust,
同时能学到点东西的方案
and learn from.
一段简单的代码通常只能展示出一个具体方案的一小部分
A sample code usually just shows you a narrow view
这很好
at a partial solution, which is great
如果你想要了解它如何工作的
if you want to know just how one thing works.
如果你想了解细节部分的话
However, when you want to see how everything fits together,
你就需要一个完整功能的示例
you need a fully functioning example.
对于搭建跨平台应用来说 这非常重要
And this is particularly important for building
因为各个部分如何很好的协作
across devices because how everything fits together
就是它本身
is the thing.
为此 我们最近发布了一个简单但是功能完整的app
And we recently released a simple but complete app just
for this purpose.
它不只是一个你可以搭建的
This is not the only kind of thing
随处可见的应用
that you can build to be ubiquitous.
记住这一点
Remember that.
他是一个一类app的概览
But rather, it's just a look at one kind of app
还有如何搭建这样一个应用
and how it can be built with these ideas in mind.
通用 Android 音乐 播放器
The universal Android Music Player.
还记得我刚刚说的随时随地听音乐吗
Remember I was just talking about listening to music
everywhere?
这个app能帮你实现
This app helps you do that.
他可以在你的手机上，手表上，电视机上
And it works on your phone, your watch, your television--
不管是Google Cast还是后边的Android TV，当然 还有车上
both Android TV soon and Google Cast-- and of course, your car.
同时也开源在Github上
And it's completely open source on GitHub.
这是链接
There's the URL.
比方说你现在有一个多媒体app
Now, let's say you have a media app that's
在一个Activity上构建
built around an activity.
这很常见
This is pretty common.
这对于单设备 单应用是足够的
And that was just fine for an app on a device.
但是如果你想支持更多的设备
But if you want to support more devices, what you usually do
你想到的可能是扩展这个Activity
is you either expand that activity,
或者为每一种设备开发一个新的
or you create new ones for each new device.
这也不算糟 直到你意识到
That's still not so bad until you realize that you probably
你得回顾你的设计
have to revisit your app's overall design each
每次调整消息传递 播放锁
and every time to coordinate new message passing, play
诸如此类的
locks, and that kind of thing.
现在 你可以实现一个稳定的核心服务
Instead, you're going to want a solid core central service that
可以轻松扩展每个新功能
extends easily to each new form factor.
有一个Android API可以实现这个
There's an Android API that makes this straightforward.
UAMP 是基于媒体浏览服务 和 媒体回话 构建的
UAMP is built around this media browser service and media
session.
这是一种你可以在Lollopop上搭建你的应用
So this is a way that you would build your app on Lollipop
你可以让你的播放器后台播放
so that you could have media keep playing in the background,
在锁屏状态下操作 等等
be controlled from the lock screen, and so forth.
也可以实现让多设备
It's also a great way to allow multiple devices
像核心服务的用户一样运行
to act as consumers of a central service
而不是Activity上的所有东西
rather than everything built in activities that need
都需要单独配置
to independently coordinate.
媒体浏览服务持有所有媒体资源的树结构
The media browser service maintains a tree structure
比如一个音乐列表
of all your media, such as a collection of music.
可以在本地传输和存储
And this could be either streamed or stored locally.
媒体回话记录你的应用
Media Session tracks the current state
正在播放什么
of what your app is playing.
有趣的是
Now, here's where it gets interesting.
所有的东西 不管是手机app
Everything, whether it's your phone app,
Android TV Android Auto
Android TV, Android Auto-- they're
都是媒体浏览服务和媒体会话的客户
all consumers of the Media Browser Service and Media
Session.
比如你的手机和
Let's say you've got your phone hooked up
Android Auto绑定了
to Android Auto like this.
左边那个app
So the companion app on the left, that's
也就是Android Auto端应用
the Android Auto Companion app.
这个app负责绘制用户界面
And that app is responsible for drawing the user interface
在车载终端上显示图像
and sending those pixels to the vehicle display.
同时 链接到媒体浏览服务
This app also connects to the Media Browser Service.
向服务发送查询请求
And it queries it to get the tree structure
以获得你的app的媒体库的树结构
of your apps media library.
车主通过触屏或者语音搜索
The driver of the car then selects the song,
切歌
either the touch screen or through voice search,
然后Android Auto就会通过媒体会话
and then Android Auto will use Media Session
运行回调函数
to run your callbacks.
这在Android Auto上非常棒 因为作为开发者
And this is great on Android Auto because as a developer,
你再也不用担心如何才让用户接口
you never have to worry about the details of making
在驾驶期间更安全
a user interface that's safe for driving.
Android把这些都做好了
Android Auto takes care of all of that for you.
只需要一个可访问的音乐服务 用来传输数据
It just needs the music service available to get the data
和控制回调
and handle playback.
左边这个app 还可以是别的东西
And the app on the left, it could be anything.
可以是Android Wear
It could be Android Wear .
可以是你某个app上的一个Activity
It could be just another activity in your same app
这个app同时操作Android TV
handling Android TV.
或者是Google Cast
Or maybe it's handling Google Cast.
这些都行 以为他的设置机制
Any of these will work because of how it's set up.
我们不需要每次添加一个新功能的时候
We don't have to rewire the app each and every time we
都要去做适配
add a new form factor.
相反 我们有了这个稳定的中央服务
Instead, we have this solid central service
可以轻松的扩展任何功能
that extends easily to each new form factor.
你只需要简单地访问音乐服务
You simply access the music service
为任何上下文为你的用户
for any context that makes sense for your user.
回想一下我之前说的
Now, remember what I said earlier.
这当然不是惟一的方式
This is certainly not the only way
实现通用app 或者惟一的有用的通用app
to make a ubiquitous app or the only ubiquitous app that
makes sense.
他给你提供了一个想法
It simply gives you an idea of how
如何构建一个高扩展性的应用
to structure a common app such as a music
比如一个音乐播放器
player for extensibility.
你是用的定制的API
The specific APIs you use are of course
完全取决于你的实际情况
going to depend on your use case,
你如何实现我们谈到的最佳实践
how you implement the best practices we talked about,
还有你的model和controller放在哪
and where you keep your model and your controller.
可能在手机终端
It could be on the phone.
也可能在云上
It could be in the cloud.
可以在任何有必要的地方
It could be wherever that make sense for your service.
我们来看一下一些可参考的例子
Let's take a look at a few examples of apps
用户可以使用的
shipped and available to users that are
在今天做这样的事的
doing this kind of thing today.
iHeartRadio 为用户提供广播 音乐 新闻 博客 体育
iHeartRadio-- it brings radio, music, news, podcasts, sports,
等等
and more to users.
你甚至可以建立你自己的频道
And you can even make your own custom stations.
使用非常方便
It's easy to use.
也是免费的
And it's free.
我很喜欢这个app
I love this app.
最重要的一点 也是我最喜欢的地方
And best of all-- my favorite thing--
我可以随时随地使用它
it's available wherever I go.
在Android Wear上
It's on Android Wear.
在Android TV上
You can Cast to your TV.
甚至是在车上
You can even use it in the car.
还有一个app WhatsApp
Another great app is WhatsApp messenger.
发送消息 照片
It's great for messaging, sending photos,
讨论组 等等等等
group chat, and a lot more.
很久之前在手机上就有这个app了
And it's been available for phones for a long while.
现在Android Wear和Android Auto上也有了
And it's also available on Android Wear and Android Auto.
你看懂这里的模式了吗
Do you see the pattern here?
这就是这些应用中的一个
This is one of those applications like music
你想随时随地使用的 比如音乐
where you expect it to work everywhere.
然后它做到了
And it does.
你可以顺着这个思路想想
You can keep the conversation going whether you're
在你等电话接通的时候 散步的时候
waiting in line with your phone, on a walk with your watch,
或者开车的是时候
or a quick road trip with your car.
最后一个 食谱
And last, Cookbook.
旨在给用户带来烹饪的乐趣 和烹饪秘诀搜索
Cookbook aims to bring users the joy of cooking and sharing
记录烹饪时间 食材清单
with Recipe Search, calculated prep time, shopping
等等
list, and more.
如果你像我一样 常常把厨房弄得乱糟糟的
And if you're like me, you like to get everything as messy
这很好
in the kitchen as possible, which
因为他在任何我弄乱的地方都能使用
is great because it works on all the things I can get messy.
你可以用手机访问
It works on the phone.
也可以在手表 电视上查看你的食谱
You can also load your recipes up on your watch or your TV,
as well.
现在 如果你想把你的app做成像
Now, if you'd like to do with your app what these apps
这些app一样
have done.
可以在普适计算的课程中获取更多详细信息
you can find a lot more detail on the Ubiquitous Computing
这个课程几周内会在Udacity上开课
course that's launching on Udacity in the coming weeks.
这是Android Nano degree课程的一部分
It's part of the Android Nano degree.
很快就会上线
And it's going to be available very soon.
课程内容涵盖可穿戴设备 智能家居
It covers wearables, living room,
车载设备 这些我们今天提到的东西 不过更详细
and auto in much more detail than we talked about today.
讨论的时候
There's an old saying that I keep
我反复提到一点
coming back to when we're thinking about this space.
在构建应用的时候
Sometimes, when building apps-- and we're
有时候 我们只见树木不见森林
all guilty of this-- we forget to see
简单地说 就是我们
the forest for the trees, which is to say,
太关注于我们眼前的问题
we get so focused on that one thing in front of us
忘记了我们实际上
that we forget that we're building
是在技术和用户在实际生活中建立联系
a relationship with the user across their lives,
across their technology.
为了实现这一点 我应该在任何用户需要的时候
And to be really valuable, we should be present in their life
提供我们的应用
whenever it makes sense to them.
为了实现这一点 我们应该在最开始的时候
To this end, we should build with ubiquity in mind
关注通用性 然后逐渐扩展新的东西
from the beginning and extend to new form factors over time.
要实现这些的需要的工具和设计知识
And the tools and design knowledge
已经有现成的了
that are required for this are available.
随手就能获取到
And they're at your fingertips.
我们只需要开始去做
We just need to get started.
然后我们就能知道我们能实现多远的未来
And then we're going to find out how much further we can go.
举个例子 Nest program的工作
For example, the Works with Nest program
已经让智能家居成为可能
is making the potential of the thoughtful home real.
我们可以在他们的网站上获取更多信息
You can learn more on their website.
还有 昨天发布的 Project Brillo
Also, announced yesterday was project Brillo.
这是一个为网络应用设计的操作系统
This is an operating system for the internet of things.
从Android移植而来 能够在最小占用的
It's derived from Android and able to run on devices
设备上运行
with a minimal footprint.
核心功能包括网络连接
Core functionality includes connectivity
和模块管理
and scaled management.
当然 和昨天提到的Weave一起用的话
And of course, when you pair with Weave,
对普通用户来说
also talked about yesterday, setup and discovery
安装和使用就很容易了
becomes effortless for the user.
所有设备都可以兼容
And devices can all be compatible
并且共同工作
and work with each other.
这是我们做的一项功能
This is the future of what we do.
我们应该携手并进
And we should get together.
继续讨论
And we should talk about it more.
今天宣布一下 我们的后续工作
So also announcing today, we're going to do just that.
希望大家来参与第一届通用计算大会
I hope you can join us for first conference
我们会和许多企业一起合作
on ubiquitous computing as we get together
为用户提供
as friends across companies and industries
交互更好 更极致
to work towards more interoperability and ultimately
更有价值的服务
more value for all of our users.
通过这个链接注册
Please head to this link to sign up
及早获取信息
and be the first in line to hear more.
如果可以的话
And if you like, let us know what
告诉我们你对大会的期待
you want from this conference.
比如你要演讲
Maybe you want to speak.
或者以其他的方式参与进来
Or maybe there's another way you want to get involved.
一起来吧
Let's build this together.
参与进来 了解一下 如何在更多的
Please dive in and learn so that you can reach
场景下为用户提供服务
your users in even more places.
我们随后会深入地讨论这些事情
And we can really start to have a deep conversation about all
these things.
在我右边再远一点
Now, over here in the area to my right,
有许多穿着红色T恤的人
you'll see all these people in lovely red shirts.
我们会在那个沙盒里
We're actually going to be taking Q&amp;A
一起进行提问环节
as a group out in the sandbox.
希望大家能够参与
We hope you join us there.
可以体验一下设备
We can play with devices.
可以聊聊你在做的app
We can talk about your specific apps.
我们可以好好的聊一聊
And we can really engage in a conversation right out
就在那个沙盒里
in the sandbox.
谢谢
Thank you very much.